Guide to the Bobbye S. Ortiz Papers, 1919-1993 and undated (bulk 1950-1990) RL.00978
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Index Card Catalog Series, undated
  - Asia (Box 35-36)
  - Social Sciences and Humanities (Box 35-36)
  - Sociology (Box 35-36)
  - Anthropology (Box 35-36)
  - Philosophy (Box 35-36)
  - Psychology (Box 35-36)
  - Science (Box 35-36)
  - History (Box 35-36)
  - Political Science (Box 35-36)
  - Art (Box 35-36)
  - Religion (Box 35-36)
  - Miscellaneous Topics (Box 35-36)
  - Reference (Box 35-36)
  - Current Events (Box 35-36)
  - Spanish Civil War (Box 35-36)
  - Cancer (Box 35-36)
  - Other Tapes (USE COPIES MUST BE MADE): (Box 36)
    - 3 unidentified tapes (reels) (Box 36)
- Oversize Materials, [192-?]-[1980s]
  Consist primarily of oversize pieces from the Cultural Artifacts and Photographs Series. Posters in this series provide excellent examples of the use of visual arts by late 20th century social movements. All oversize materials have been cross-listed in the main series and subseries to which they belong. Materials formerly housed in Oversize Folders 6-11 have been boxed into Box 38.
  [This series is partially closed. Contact Research Services.]
  - Cartoon Drawing, Viki and Camilo (Personal Files Series) [CLOSED until 2025] (Box 37)
  - Diplomas (BA, MA), Founder's Day Award (Education) [CLOSED until 2025] (Box 37)
  - Robert Colodny Photograph (Photographs) [CLOSED until 2025] (Box 37)
  - Unidentified Matted Photographs (Photographs) (Box 37)
  - "Housing in Revolutionary Cuba" (Geographic) (Box 37)
  - Panoramic photograph in which Louis Suckle (BSO's father) can be seen, [192-?] (Photographs.) (Oversize-folder 3)
  - Posters (Cultural Artifacts), Oversize Folders 6-11 (Box 38)
  - Posters: Africa and Middle East (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Posters: Europe (France and Italy) (Oversize-folder 2)
  - Art Museum Posters (France) (Oversize-folder 5)
  - One poster from Student/Worker Strikes, France, June [1968?] (Oversize-folder 4)
  - Posters: U.S. Movements: (Black Panthers, Socialists and Marxists, Women's Liberation, Anti-War movement) (Oversize-folder 12)
  - Posters: Latin America, 2 folders (Oversize-folder 14, 16)
  - Posters: Asia (Vietnam and China) (Oversize-folder 15)
  - Posters: International Women's Day (various countries): Original artwork done for Bobbye and Viki (Oversize-folder 13)
- Phonograph Records Series, [195-]-[198-] and undated
  Recordings collected by Bobbye Ortiz mainly from the 1950s through the 1980s. The categories of General (Europe, Latin America, South America), Pop, Folk, Labor movement, Protest, and Miscellaneous have collections of varied content. Many of the popular recordings (not only in the Pop category, but also in the countries divisions) contain protest songs, for example. Anti-Vietnam War movementsongs may be found in various countries as well as in the categories of Pop, Folk, Labor, and Protest.
  Subseries are based on type of recording (12 inch, 10 inch, and 45 rpm) and are divided into sections representing countries or subject categories. Within each country or category, the recordings are arranged by performer, then further by title if there is more than one recording by that artist.
  - Twelve Inch Recordings
    - Angola (Box 38)
      - #1 Title: Contra a ideia da violncia a violncia da ideia
        - Performer: Luis Cilia (Box 38)
          Ptria lugar de Exilio, Gabriel, Cantiga de Amigo, Fecundou-te, Canto de Esperana, Contra a ideia da violncia a violncia da ideia, Voz Suspensa, Caminho Longe, O Poema Original, Sei Que Me Esperas
          Record Label: Le Chant du Monde, LDX 74538
      - #2 Title: Les uns par les autres
        - Performer: Luis Cilia (Box 38)
          Antico de um mundo novo, Serventes, Fala do homen nascido, Dez reis de esperanca, Adeus trigo, Portugal resiste, Poema a boca fechada, Venham eis, Ecloga em tempo de guerra, Ternura, Heranca
          Record Label: Gravure Universelle, MN - 10012
      - #3 Title: Meu pas
        - Performer: Luis Cilia (Box 38)
          Meu pas, A bola, Basta, Resiste, Duas melodias, Exilio, Canta, Aqu ficas, Canto do desertor, Bairro de lata, Sou barco, O que menos importa, Guitarras como tristeza, O menino negro nao entrou na roda, Regresso, Canao final, canao de sempre
          Record Label: Le Chant du Monde, LDX 74308
      - #4 Title: Toques y cantos yorubas
        - Performer: CNC (Box 38)
          Cantos para Elegua, Cantos para Oggun, Cantos para Yemaya, Cantos para Shango, Cantos para Oshun, Cantos para Obatala, Cantos para Oya, Cantos para Oshosi, Cantos para Babalu-Aye, Cantos para Elegua
          Record Label: EGREM, LD-CNC-2
      - #5 Title: Angola: A vitoria certa! Movimiento Popular de libertao de Angola (Victory is Certain! Songs of the Liberation Army of the MPLA)
        - Performer: Liberation Support Movement (Box 38)
          Side 1: Revolution, Revolution! Shouts, Drums and Singing Victory or Death, MPLA, Defender of All the People, MPLA, Angolan Revolution, Spoken Introduction, Allelujah, Papa ni Mama, Untitled fragments, The Comandante is with the Revolution; Comandante, Come in a Hurry; Brothers Listen My Heart Breathes; Separation is Easy; The Portuguese in Angola; Portuguese, Leave Angola, Anthem of the MPLA
          Side 2: MPLA Invulsi, Monetu ua Kassule, Deba, Dr. Neto, Dituminu, Ufolo, Kaputu, Etu Tuan' Angola, Mon'a Ngamb' Eh!
          Record Label: Paredon, P1002
    - Argentina
      - #6 Title: Le chant du coq - Cantate (Cantate del gallo cantor)
        - Performer: Cuarteto Cedrn (Box 38)
          Record Label: Polydor, 23934 063
      - #7 Title: Suertes (Chances)
        - Performer: Cuarteto Cedrn (Box 38)
          Side 1: Sobre la poesia y el combate, Sobre un cierto tipo de muerte, Sobre un cierto tipo de vida, Sobre la llama que nada el agua fria, Medulas que han, Suertes gloriosamente Ardido
          Side 2: Diagonales, A Luis Luchi, La plantita, Temas de la ciudad, sonico
          Record Label: Polydor, 2473 082
      - #8 Title: En vivo
        - Performer: Nacha Guevara, Alberto Favero (Box 38)
          Side 1: Presentacin, Yo soy la Nacha, Las damas de beneficencia, Soy snob, La mucamita, Mi hombre, El vals del minuto
          Side 2: Te quiero, Versos sencillos, Un Padrenuestro Latinoamericano, Yo te nombro
          Record Label: Discos NCL, NCL-LP-004
      - #9 Title: Habla el Che Guevera (Difusion Musical) (Box 38)
        Side 1: Homenaje de Carlos Altamirano, Habla Ernesto Guevara, Carta de Haydee Santamaria, Habla Ernesto Guevara, Himno Latinoamericano
        Side 2: Homenaje de Enrique Lihn Carrasco, Habla Ernesto Guevara, Homenaje de Juvencio Valle, Fidel Castro lee la carta de despedida, Habla Ernesto Guevara, Himno de los guerrilleros
        Record Label: Astral, America Hoy, VBP-295
      - #10 Title: Cesar Vallejo: Voz viva de America Latina poemas
        - Performer: Claudio Obregon (Box 38)
          Side 1: Espergesia, A mi hermano Miguel, Los pasos lejanos, Dios, El poeta a su amada, Los dados eternos, Todos los das amanezco a ciegas, Oh las cuatro paredes de la celda, Un hombre pasa con un pan al hombro; Considerando en fro, imparcialmente; La clera que quiebra al hombre en nios
          Side 2: Los mendigos pelean por Espaa, Hombre de Extremadura; Espaa, aparta de m este Cliz; La rueda del Hambriento, Intensidad y altura, Los heraldos negros, Piedra negra sobre una piedra blanca, Masa
          Record Label: Universidad Nacional Autonoma de Mexico
      - #11 Title: Circling Free
        - Performer: Marsie Silvestro (Box 38)
          Side 1: Circling Free, Oh Tell Me, See How I Rise, Peace Flowing Like a River, Who Will Go, Spirit of Loving
          Side 2: My Friend You Are a Miracle, Renew the Earth, Spinning, Gettin' Tired Blues, For Everyone You Take, Blessing Song, Stand Together
          Record Label: Moonsong Productions, MS 333
      - #12 Title: Mercedes Sosa (Coleccon Recital, Los Grandes Artistas)
        - Performer: Mercedes Sosa (Box 38)
          Side 1: Al jardin de la republica, Duerme negrito, Chayita del vidalero, Tristeza, Alfonsina y el mar, Zamba del Chaguanco, Cancin con todos
          Side 2: Si se calla el cantor, Cancin para un nio en la calle, La oncena, Cancin del derrumbe indio, Zamba para no morir, Gracias a la vida
          Record Label: Philips, 6347091
      - #13 Title: Hasta la victoria (Coleccon Recital, Los Grandes Artistas)
        - Performer: Mercedes Sosa, Vol. 2 (Box 38)
          Side 1: Balderrama, Hombre en el tiempo, La arenosa, Si se calla el cantor, Hasta la victoria
          Side 2: Los hermanos, Plegaria a un labrador, Violin de becho, La pobrecita, Cruzando por la ciudad, Canto vital
          Record Label: Philips, 15064
      - #14 Title: Textos politicos, 10 aos de compromiso, 1960-1980
        - Performer: Alfredo Zitarrosa (Box 38)
          Side 1: Mire amigo, Nilonga caera, No se puede, Chamarrita de los milicos, Milonga de contrapunto
          Side 2: Diez decimas de autocrtica, La cancin quiere, Decimas de saludo al publico argentino, Adagio en mi pas, Desde el exilio
          Record Label: Foton, LPS 030
    - Brazil
      - #15 Title: Brsil
        - Performer: Serto & Favelas (Box 38)
          Side 1: Carcara, Funeral do lavrador, Cancao da terra, Sina de caboclo, Cheganca, Pau de Arara
          Side 2: Opiniao, Nega dina, Pedro Pedreiro; Feio, nao e bonito; Zelao, Cicatriz
          Record Label: Le Chant du Monde, Gravure Universelle, LDX 7 4346
      - #16 Title: Cartola: Documento Inedito (Box 38)
        Side 1: Que sejam benvindos, Autonomia, Acontece, Senes
        Side 2: O inverno do meu tempo, Que sejas bem feliz; D-me graas, senhora; Quem me v sorrindo
        Record Label: Estudio Eldorado, 59.82.0396
    - Chile
      - #17 Title: Chant pour les enfants du Chili
        - Performer: George Brassens, Julien Clerc, Jean Ferrat, Juliette Greco, Maxime le Forestier, Colette Magny, Yves Montand, Mouloudji, Georges Moustaki, Serge Reggiani, Francesca Solleville, Anne Sylvestre (Box 38)
          Side 1: Le petit cheval, Paris couleur novembre, Juste comme un enfant, Requiem pour n'importe qui, Abel Cain mon fils, Dejeuner de soleil
          Side 2: Les feuilles mortes, L'colier soldat, Mourir d'enfance, Faut vivre, Camarade Chili, Mon chant est un ruisseau
          Record Label: Secours Populaire Francais, P 1977sPF
      - #18 Title: Los chilenos
        - Performer: Juan Capra (Box 38)
          Side 1: La Huella, Somos pajaros libres, Los pueblos americanos, La flor que anda de mano en mano, El angel est llorando, Romance de Juan Hilario Alvarez
          Side 2: La cancin del minero, La paloma, Tengo un pena, Contrapunto el aguila americana y el condor chileno, Resfaloza dek Vietnam, Las pariciones
          Record Label: Barclay Panache, 820 180
      - #19 Title: Chili canto a lo humano
        - Performer: Juan Capra (Box 38)
          Side 1: Supe en el norte que habia, Con el silencio e la noche, Errante golondrina, Cuando llegaron los indios
          Side 2: De las alturas del cielo, En el cenaculo estaba, Cuando te vai a casar, Arriba de un chirimolli
          Record Label: LDX 74407
      - #20 Title: Chile canta e lotta, Canti popolari cileni di ieri e di oggi, ( Chile Sings and Struggles, Chilean Folksongs of Yesterday and Today)
        - Performer: Juan Capra (Box 38)
          Side 1: Dicen que no caben, Blanca flor y filumena, Dicen que los manos, Versos por padecimiento, El hundimiento del transporte "angamos", San Pedro se puso guapo, Dsen las manos
          Side 2: Bajando de los Andes, Viva balmaceda!, Tengo una pena, Sirilla, Contrapunto entre el aguila americana y el condor chileno, Yo me vuelvo para Chile
          Record Label: Albatros
      - #21 Title: La primavera muerta en el tejado, Chile 11 de septiembre 1973
        - Performer: Patricio Castillo (Box 38)
          Side 1: Cuando aparecio, Las manadas, Pichona sin pechon, El soldado ciego, Cuando se fue
          Side 2: Te recuerdo amanda, El arado, San Juanito y cueca de murieta, El aparecido, Madrugada
          Record Label: Canto Libre, DCP 107-DF 68
      - #22 Title: Chile Vencer: An Anthology of Chilean New Song, 1962-1973 (Box 38)
        Side 1: Gracias A La Vida, Que Dira Santo Padre, Quena En Verano, Run Run Se Fue P'al Norte, Amor
        Side 2: Inti Illimani, La Pericona, Vamos Mujer, Preguntas Por Puerto Montt, Ni Chicha Ni Limona, Las Casitas Del Barrio Alto, Al Centro De Injusticia
        Side 3: La Democracia, Il Bosco, Tolin Tolin Tolin, La Burra De Beltran, Yo Quiero Verte, Las Doradas Colinas De Bihn Xuan
        Side 4: Hermano Lloraras, No Nos Moveran, La Batea, September 11, 1973, El Pueblo Unido Jamas Sera Vencido
        Record Label: Rounder Records, 4009/4010
      - #23 Title: Poesias de Miguel Hernndez
        - Performer: Nuria Espert, Augustin Gonzalez, Jose-Miguel Velloso (Box 38)
          Side 1: El sudor, Carta, No quiso ser, Que quiere el viento de enero?, Una fotografia, Bocas de ira, Menos tu vientre, El pez mas viejo del rio, Beso soy, sombra con sombra, No pudimos ser, El ultimo y el primero, Nanas de la cebolla
          Side 2: Un carnivoro cuchillo, Me tiraste un limon y tan amargo, Fuera menos penado si no fuera, Umbrio pop la pena casi bruno, Yo se que ver y oir a un triste enfada, Te me mueres de casta y de sencilla por un senda van los hortelanos, Como el toro he nacido para el luto, Soneto final, Elegia, Me llamo barro aunque Miguel me llame, Egloga, Sino sangriento
          Record Label: La Palabra Discos Aguilar, GPE 12 102
      - #24 Title: Chile herido (Volumen 2) (Box 39)
        - Performer: Inti-Illimani (Box 39)
          Side 1: Tocata y fuga, Corazon maldito, Run run se fue pa'l norte, El aparecido, Asi como hoy matan negros, Chile herido
          Side 2: Calambito temucano, Exilada del sur, La partida, Lo que mas quiero, Ya parte el galgo terrible, El pueblo unido jamas sera vencido
          Record Label: Discos Pueblos, DP-1011
      - #25 Title: Hacia la libertad
        - Performer: Inti-Illimani (Box 39)
          Side 1: Hacia la libertad, Chile, Vientos del pueblo, Cai cai vilu, Canto a los caidos
          Side 2: Arriba quemando el sol, La patria prisonera, El arado, Cancin a Victor, Ciudad Ho Chi Minh
          Record Label: Monitor Music of the World, MFS 781
      - #26 Title: Viva Chile!
        - Performer: Inti-Illimani (2 Copies) (Box 39)
          Side 1: Fiesta del San Benito, Longuita, Cancion del poder popular, Alturas, La segunda independencia, Cueca de la C.U.T.
          Side 2: Tatati, Venceremos, Ramis, "Rin" del angelito, Subida, Simon Bolivar
          Record Label: Monitor Music of the World, MS 769
      - #27 Title: Chile Combatiente
        - Performer: Vctor Jara, Isabel Parra, Angel Parra, P. Castillo, Hctor Pavez, Quilapayn, Aparcoa, Inti-Illimani (Box 39)
          Side 1: Chile herido, Las ultimas palabras, Manifesto, Vientos del pueblo, Cancin al partido, Levntese compaero
          Side 2: La segunda independencia, Ya no es tiempo de esperar, Aqu me quedo, El rojo gota a gota ir creciendo, Cuando amanece el dia, Alerta pueblos del mundo, El pueblo unido jams ser vencido
          Record Label: Discos Foton, Le Chant du Monde, MC-0602
      - #28 Title: El derecho de vivir en paz(Vol. 2)
        - Performer: Vctor Jara, Chile's Great Singer-Poet (Box 39)
          Side 1: A Cochabamba me voy, A Luis Emilio recabarren, El derecho de vivir en paz, Camilo Torres, Ni chicha ni limona, Preguntas por puerto Montt
          Side 2: A Cuba, Abre tu ventana, La partida, El nio yuntero, Vamos por ancho, El Martillo
          Record Label: Monitor Music of the World, MFS 788
      - #29 Title: Pongo en tus manos abiertas
        - Performer: Victor Jara, Quilapayun (Box 39)
          Side 1: A Luis Emilio Recabarren, A Desalambrar, Duerme, duerme negrito, Juan sin tierra, Preguntas por Pto. Montt, "Movil" Oil Special
          Side 2: Camilo Torres, El Martillo, Te recuerdo Amanda, Zamba del Ch, Ya parte el galgo terrible, A Cochabamba me voy
          Record Label: Jota Jota, JJL-03
      - #30 Title: Karaxu! (Box 39)
        Side 1: Su nombre ardi como un pajar, La resistencia se organisa, Viviremos, Carnivalito salteo, 'Ta llegando gente al baile
        Side 2: Quebrada verde, Por America indomita, Per i morti di reggio emilia, Cueca de malloco, Candombe para Jose
        Record Label: Eleven, EL:01113
      - #31 Title: Cancin sin lmites
        - Performer: Patrio Manns (Box 39)
          Side 1: Cuando me acuerdo de mi pais, Escrito en el trigo, Carta abierta al interior de Chile, Su nombre ardio como un pajar
          Side 2: Valdivia en la niebla, Raices del llanto, Morimos solos, 1917 Cancion
          Record Label: Movie Play Serie GONG, 17.1271/0
      - #32 Title: Chile: Songs for the Resistance
        - Performer: Patricio Manns, Karaxu, Angel Parra (Box 39)
          Side 1: La cancin de Luciano, La ventana, La resistencia se organiza, Bolivariana, Solo digo compaeros
          Side 2: Miguel Enriquez, Los libertadores, La dignidad se hace costumbre, Ya no somos nosotros, Carta a mi compaero, Trabajadores al poder
          Record Label: Paredon, P-1030
      - #33 Title: Pablo Neruda, Poemas
        - Performer: Pablo Neruda (Box 39)
          Side 1: La casa de las odas, Oda al aceite, Pido silencio, Fbula de la sirena y los borrachos, El gran mantel, Sobre mi mala educacin, Dnde estar la Guillermina?
          Side 2: Testamento de Otono, Eternidad, Sonetos (VI, XXIV, XXXVIII, XXX, XXIX)
          Record Label: Universidad Nacional Autnoma de Mxico Direccin General de Difusin Cultural, VVAL-4
      - #34 Title: Pablo Neruda
        - Performer: Angel Parra (2 copies) (Box 39)
          Side 1: El Vuelo, El Tordo, El Pica Flor
          Side 2: El Piden, La Golondrina, El Cndor, El Poeta se despide de los pjaros
          Record Label: Musica de esta America, Casa de las Americas, LD-CA-6
      - #35 Title: Yo tuve una patria
        - Performer: Angel Parra (Box 39)
          Side 1: La libertad, Yo tuve una patria, Tango en Colmbes, Autorretrato, Que sera de mis hermanos, Porque maana se abriran las alamedas
          Side 2: El poeta frente al mar, El dia que vuelva a encontrar, Compaero presidente, America del sur, Levantese compaero
          Record Label: Movie Play Serie GONG, 17.0882/8
      - #36 Title: La pea de los parra
        - Performer: Isabel y Angel Parra, Grupo Chagual (2 copies) (Box 39)
          Side 1: Coplas folkloricas, Mexico '68, Coplas del vino, El rin, EL cantar tiene sentido, Los pueblos americanos
          Side 2: Zumba que zumba, Guitarra en duelo mayor, La lavandera, Canto de llegada a la tirana, A desalambrar, Pajaro madrugador
          Record Label: Pena de los Parra, VBP-284
      - #37 Title: La pena de los parra
        - Performer: Isabel Parra, Angel Parra, Patricio Manns, Rolando Alarcon (Box 39)
          Side 1: Rio Manzanares, En lota la noche es brava, Decimas del folklore venezolano, Yo defiendo a mi tierra, Parabien de la paloma, Hasta cuando compaero
          Side 2: La tropillita, Ya no canto tu nombre, La jardinera, Canto a mi America, Refalosa del morro, Los parecidos, El sacristan vivaracho
          Record Label: Demon, LPD-015
      - #38 Title: Las ultimas composiciones de Violeta Parra
        - Performer: Violeta Parra (Box 39)
          Side 1: Gracias a la vida, El "Albertio", Cantores que reflexionan, Pupila de aguila, Run Run se fue pa'l norte, La cueca de los poetas
          Side 2: Mazurquica modernica, Volver a los 17, Rin del angelito, Una copla me ha cantado, El guillatun, Pastelero a tus pasteles
          Record Label: RCA Victor, MIL/S-4136
      - #39 Title: Un rio de sangre
        - Performer: Violeta Parra, Isabel Parra, Angel Parra, Los Calchakis (Box 39)
          Side 1: Segun el favor del viento, Un rio de sangre, Santiago penando estas, Hasta cuando estas, En los jardines humanos, Arauco tiene una pena
          Side 2: Teneme en tu corazon, Cantos a lo divino, Para un presidente, Chile, Masa, La muralla
          Record Label: Arion, HARS 741-14
      - #40 Title: Quilapayun
        - Performer: Quilapayun (Box 39)
          Side 1: La paloma, El forastero, El canto del cuculi, El pueblo, La boliviana, La cueca triste
          Side 2: La cancin del minero, Dos palomitas, Por una pequena, Chispa, La perdida, El borrachito, Somos pajaros libres
          Record Label: Odeon, LDC-36614
      - #41 Title: The Siege of Santa Maria de Iquique, A People's Cantata of the Chilean nitrate miners
        - Performer: Quilapayun (Box 39)
          Record Label: Paredon, P-1019
      - #42 Title: Testimonios de la tortura en Chile (Box 39)
        Record Label: Americanto 1005
    - Cuba (Box 40)
      - #43 Title: Cuban Subversive (handwritten label on cover) (Box 40)
        Side 1: Ya tenemos hospital, El survey, Plan de machete, El son de Fengue Corra, Y eso si que no, Y en eso lleg Fidel
        Side 2: Todo por la Reforma Agraria, Canto a Camilo, Procura venir en paz, Ay cubano, Ya lo dice el refrn, Yanqui, go home
        Record Label: Olin Discos Populares, 0-1
      - #44 Title: La Mujer en la Revolucin
        - Performer: Federacion de Mujeres Cubanas (Box 40)
          Side 1: Ella salio desnuda, Campesina, Mujer del mundo tercero, La mujer posible, Zamba para una flor militante
          Side 2: Mujer bayamesa, Para una imaginaria Maria del Carmen, La mujer esta con la revolucin, Mi compaera, Madre, La mujer hoy
          Record Label: Areito, EGREM, LD-3501
      - #45 Title: Grupo Moncado
        - Performer: Grupo Moncado (Box 40)
          Side 1: O poder popular, De pueblo en pueblo, Pude ser, Decimas a Jose Antonio Echeverria, Elegia
          Side 2: Una mujer, Si digo, Folkclor negro, Son final, Huaynos, Chamame a Cuba
          Record Label: Americanto 1006
      - #46 Title: Nicolas Guillen dice sus poemas (2 copies)
        - Performer: Nicolas Guillen (Box 40)
          Side 1: Arte Poetica, Un largo lagarto verde, Cancin puertorriquea, Little Rock, Doa Maria, Muerte, Deportes, Acana, Son no. 6, El abuelo, Caminando
          Side 2: Cancin de cuna para despertar un negrito, Puedes?, Soldado aprende a tirar, No se por que piensas tu, Guitarra, Elegia, Palma sola, Agua del recuerdo, Un son para nios antillanos, El negro mar, El apellido
          Record Label: EGREM Areito, LDA-3340
      - #47 Title: Poemas de Nicolas Guillen (Grabacin realizada en Chile - Julio 1967)
        - Performer: Nicolas Guillen (Box 40)
          Side 1: Aviso, El caribe, Guitarras, Escarabajos, La pajarita del papel, La osa mayor, El aconcagua, Los usereros, Los ros, Seora, Al pblico, La sed, El hambre, Intittriz, Las nubes, Los vientos, El tigre, Cicln, Ave Fnix
          Side 2: Clinch, El cangrejo, Gangster, KKK, Las aguilas, Monos, Luna, Tenor, Polica, El chulo, Reloj, Aviso, Oradores, El sueo, Gorila, Tontn Macoute, Bomba atmica, La estrella polar, Salida
          Record Label: Astral VBP. 216
      - #48 Title: Himnos y marchas de Cuba (Box 40)
        Side 1: Himno invasor, Desde yara hasta la sierra, Hasta siempre Cuba, Marcha de la revolucin, Adelante, Cuba socialista
        Side 2: Marcha del 26 de julio, Venceremos, Muerte al invasor, Al pueblo, Patria liberada, Viva el socialismo
        Record Label: EGREM Areito, LD-4002
      - #49 Title: Musaico cubano
        - Performer: Orquesta del Festival (Box 40)
          Side 1: Mosaico cubano, Perlas
          Side 2: Quiereme mucho, Tu, Flor de yumuri, Para ti, El mambi
          Record Label: EGREM Areito, LDS 3319
      - #50 Title: Rabo de Nube Vol. 1
        - Performer: Silvio Rodriguez (Box 40)
          Side 1: Vamos a andar, Rabo de nube, El dia feliz que esta llegando, Te amare y despues, Fabula de los tres hermanos